How does Math.random work to sort an array?

we can use .sort() method to sort an array, with compare function, we can sort the array ascending and descending.

1.
array.sort(function(a, b){return a - b});

a - b will return a negative value : ascending array, smaller elements are in the front.

2.
array.sort(function(a, b){return b - a});

b - a will return a positive value: descending array, bigger elements are in the front.

These two are the most common method with sort method.
And by using Math.random() we can create a random sorted array.

array.sort (function(a, b) {return 0.5 - Math.random()});

the key point is 0.5 - Math.random() will return a value either positive or negative.
If Math.random() is bigger than 0.5, it will have negative value, if smaller, it'll have a positive value.

But this is where I got stuck, let's say if the value of 0.5 - Math.random() is negative, why the array is not a ascending 
one but a random one?

After a long time thinking, I finally realized that the sort method compares two elements at one time, so it doesn't finish 
sorting the whole array at one time, but many times of comparing.
That's why it can create a random array because the value may be positive when it compares the first and the second element,
but then has a negative value when compares the second and the third elements.


